Me.
Nick Bowman: Alright.
kylie jue: Can
kylie jue: Folks, see my screen.
Eshani Jha: Yeah, cool.
Eshani Jha: Thanks.
kylie jue: Awesome. So yeah, so my question to yesterday. But as I'm introducing the lecture. Go ahead and throw an example of an order data instead of order data that you've encountered in your life. So today we're going to talk about an order data structures specifically sets and maps.
kylie jue: And going back to our roadmap, here we are on the last new day of abstract data structures on census maps will have one that sort of brings it all together, tomorrow, but this is the last day where you're going to be learning new content new abstract data structures.
kylie jue: So today's question is when is it appropriate to use different types of an order data structures.
kylie jue: And then we're going to be covering just two of those sets and maps. So a little bit of the review.
kylie jue: Of the whirlwind of order data structures that we went over yesterday, we started out with learning about a grid which is a 2D array defined with a specific width and a specific height and we learned about the three different ways to declare a grid.
kylie jue: Which include initializing it right when you create it with the number of rows and columns or with actually the values inside of the rows and columns are in each cell as well.
kylie jue: We also took a little bit of a side tangent and learned about structure which are a way to bundle different types of information. So kind of like a way of creating your own custom data structure.
kylie jue: And just as a note here for structure. Again, you won't have to define them yourself for the next assignment or two.
kylie jue: But you will be using on the next assignment, one that is predefined in the Stanford c++ libraries and that is the good location instruct
kylie jue: And what the grid location structure does is it makes it a lot more convenient for you to store grid location so specifically grouping together rows and columns into this grid location structure which stores two integers and the way you define and
kylie jue: The way you define instructors you use these curly braces or you can just access their members using the dot notation directly
kylie jue: And then we learned about two other on to two other order data structures. The first was a queue, which looks like a line.
kylie jue: The convention here is first in first out. So the first thing you in queue into the key will be the first thing that you also DQ from it. And the last person in will be the last person served
kylie jue: For a stack you could think about it like an actual stack. When you look about look at this on that side when you're defining you rotate it.
kylie jue: Clockwise so you turn it on its side and the top ends up on the right, but the only things you can do are push pop and top. So looking at the thing on the top of the stack or at the end of the stack.
kylie jue: And the general convention here is last in first out. So the last thing in will also be the first thing that comes out.
kylie jue: And this is sort of just summary of what we've looked at so far. So we've learned about four different data types abstract data types.
kylie jue: Abstract data structures. And so those are vectors grids queues and stacks.
kylie jue: Some of them, how they all are ordered, but some of them have indices, you can actually access and others, you can't actually access the elements by index. And those are the cues in the stacks.
kylie jue: So just to warm up for today I wanted to do a quick activity. Some of you may have heard of this game. It's called towers of paranoia.
kylie jue: If you have heard of the game in this first breakout room. I encourage you to just let your breakout roommates, try to figure out the problem first before you jump in with how to solve the problem, but you're welcome to share the solution as well. So this is how the game works.
kylie jue: So there are three towers, there is the source, the auxiliary and the destination and you want to get all of the disks.
kylie jue: From the source peg, all the way to the destination peg and the way you'd have to do this though is you move the District one at a time.
kylie jue: Or it's the end but there are a few rules that you have to follow. You're only allowed to move one disc at a time and you cannot place a larger disk on top of a smaller just so if I put
kylie jue: Disk one on the auxiliary peg. I could not then put the source disk on top of it. The bigger dis which we're going to represent by larger integers have to be beneath it.
kylie jue: So the question is, how do you do it. How do you go from this beginning state to this end state. And you can imagine where we're going with this. These are
kylie jue: Implemented as stacks in the actual code, but I don't want you to think about the code yet.
kylie jue: First, we're going to put you into breakout rooms and I would love to have you just discussed how would you solve this problem. And we'll give you five minutes for that.
kylie jue: And before bringing you back and discussing the pseudo code for it. But again, don't know code. Don't worry about Ed workspaces yet. We're just going to put you in breakout rooms and I want you to discuss
kylie jue: How would you go from here to here. And this is just a practice with some algorithmic thinking that will then translate into actual abstract data structure code. And the second part of this. So Nick, could you open up the breakout rooms.
Thanks.
kylie jue: Alright, so hopefully you're joining the breakout rooms.
kylie jue: Zoom does this thing when people go into breakout rooms with a bar just moves to the left. I don't know if that's a something other people see but
kylie jue: All right, most people in there. It seems like yeah okay if you are watching from home or not live. I keep saying watching from home. But everyone's watching from home, probably
kylie jue: If you're not watching this live. Go ahead and you can pause the video here. I encourage you to try to think about the solution. Give yourself like five minutes or so to try to figure it on your on your own. Don't look it up. But, see if you can figure it out.
Are you talking
kylie jue: I can't hear you.
kylie jue: I can very quietly.
Nick Bowman: Hello, no.
kylie jue: Yeah, that's a lot better. Okay.
Nick Bowman: I'm sorry, just how long total you want for this.
kylie jue: Five minutes. So once we hit like 39 or I guess 40 3039
Nick Bowman: Well, I would say maybe 38 I started, I think I hit it at like 34 so
kylie jue: That's fine, just
kylie jue: If you want to give a broadcast message up 37 or now and tell them one more minute to discuss that would be great.
kylie jue: Is it OK for your neck on zoom side, you're able to like control the breaker and stuff.
kylie jue: Go. Sounds good.
kylie jue: Did you set the return time to like 10 seconds. Okay, cool.
kylie jue: Right. So it seems like people are mostly back. It looks like. So I'm going to go ahead and talk about how would you actually solve this problem.
kylie jue: So let's talk about it in terms of a little bit of the abstract data structures that you've been learning about. So if we think about each of these pays as stacks.
kylie jue: The source peg will start with 321 right at the top of the stack is one and which is this end over here.
kylie jue: And then you have the auxiliary stack. And then you have the destination and you want the destination stack to become 321 by the end. So the question is, how would you actually do this.
kylie jue: So some of you if you've solved the problem before, or if you were able to get there. Great. This is the pseudo code for how you would actually solve this problem for three
kylie jue: Three desks. So you start over here, then you move disk one the top disk over to the destination peg.
kylie jue: And then you're going to move disk to over to the auxiliary peg and then you move the first disc back onto the accelerator pack so you end up in stage three.
kylie jue: And then you're going to move. Once these two are out of the way you move the largest disk disk three over to the end and
kylie jue: And then you can do the same thing where you move this little one over to the source peg so that you can move the second one, and then you're able to
kylie jue: Move this last first disk disk number one over to the destination. So these are sort of the seven steps the pseudo code that you are going to need to solve it.
kylie jue: So what we're going to do now is we're going to put you back into the breakout rooms to actually code up the solution. And here's how it's going to look
kylie jue: So we're going to, we have these Edward spaces. There are instructions for with the rules in case you want to refer back to the rules for towers of annoying.
kylie jue: But what you're doing is you're just filling out this function here, and it's called towers of paranoia three discs and what you want to do is you want to populate this destination stack.
kylie jue: With 321 by just using source and auxiliary and doing your push and pop
kylie jue: Operations here. And so we've automatically populated source for you here for you here and auxiliary is just an empty stack that you can use along the way.
kylie jue: This is sort of a challenge problem, which I'll leave for later. So don't worry about it but just fill out this one and then when you run the program again using if you open up the terminal and then type make run. It'll print out the resulting
kylie jue: Stack to make sure you've done it correctly. So Nick, could you go ahead and open up the breakout rooms will give people like five minutes to go ahead and do this. Feel free to screenshot this if you want this to refer you
Nick Bowman: Did you want to just cut it up in hand for the recording.
Nick Bowman: That is a good point, yeah.
kylie jue: I can go ahead and code it up.
Nick Bowman: I'm not gonna do it afterwards.
kylie jue: Yeah, I'm
Nick Bowman: Just review the code documents on people.
kylie jue: Yeah, I think that's a good idea. I think
kylie jue: I'll go ahead and code it well.
kylie jue: Folks are in their breakout rooms and then I'll review what I've coated
kylie jue: Alright, so for those of you watching
kylie jue: asynchronously. So what we're going to do is we're going to go ahead and try to populate destination and just so that it's easier. I'm going to do a side by side here so I can see the pseudo code next to what I'm working on.
To do.
kylie jue: Alright, perfect. So what we want to do is we want to populate the destination stack so that it also looks like 321 so let's go ahead and actually do this coat. So first you want to move disk one to destination.
kylie jue: So what we're going to do, and each disc. Here's an integer. So as an intermediate. I'm going to call this disc like current
kylie jue: Let's see. Yeah, let's just call this current desk. So we're going to have the current desk, we need to grab this sequence. So we're going to do source dot pop and then we want to move it over to
kylie jue: The auxiliary pin. So we're going to say auxiliary push her desk and those are the first two steps. Step three moves disk.
kylie jue: I'm so sorry. That is not what I want. I made a mistake here. Okay. Current does. Let's call this, let's just make sure this is super clear disk.
kylie jue: One. So we're going to say source stop pop and we are going to move it to the destination. So actually, instead of trying to think about the clearest way to do this instead of actually, let's do this.
kylie jue: I think this is the clearest way to make it clear that you're not actually because you can't actually
kylie jue: When you're moving these this in real life. You're just going to move them directly between pack so I'm going to push as I pop. So once I pop off.
kylie jue: The first disc on sports. I'm going to go ahead and add it to the destination. So that is step one.
kylie jue: Step two, we want to move disk to onto the auxiliary pin. So what are we going to push on to accelerate. We're going to do source, pop, pop, again, and that's going to be disk to
kylie jue: For this one, now we want to move disk one onto. Exactly. So what we're gonna do is we're going to do destination top push sore stop. Nope, sorry auxiliary push
So our destination.
kylie jue: Pop.
kylie jue: And again, this is step three. So,
kylie jue: Now what we want to do is step four. So we want to move desk three, which was currently on source on to the destination. So we want to do destination.
kylie jue: Push source dot pop
kylie jue: And so now source will be empty and it should look like the state and four and now on. Step five. What we're gonna do is we're going to just one on to source. So I want to say source dot push auxiliary pop
kylie jue: And that was. Step five. And so. Step six. We're moving disk to onto the destination from this middle pin. So we're going to say destination push
kylie jue: Auxiliary pop
kylie jue: And then the last thing we're going to do is we are going to push from the source on to the destination. So we will do destination push sore stop pop
kylie jue: Alright, so now let's run this code and see if destination has correctly changed, and here are past the results in by reference important that it's by reference. And then we're going to put it out here.
kylie jue: And we have three sweet.
Nick Bowman: Alright.
Nick Bowman: That's 45
kylie jue: bring people back
kylie jue: Alright, as folks are coming back in. I went ahead and coded this while you were in your breakout rooms.
kylie jue: But I'll just talk through it really quickly. Each of these lines corresponds to one of these seven steps. And basically what I'm doing. Each time is I push
kylie jue: Something, but I'm popping on to a different peg right and you may have used intermediate
kylie jue: Integers. If you found that easier to follow. But for me, this is sort of representative of the fact that when you pull something off of a peg. You have to immediately put it on to another part. You can't just sort of like, hold it to the side.
kylie jue: So what we're doing right and that's very first step is you are taking putting on to the destination pin. The first thing that you're pulling off of source which is why this is step one.
kylie jue: And then I'm not going to walk through every single one. But we will make this available in the lecture public lecture workspace after
kylie jue: After lecture, but this is these are the sort of separate steps represented as staff operations. And then if you print at the end you'll end up seeing that you do get 321 in the result here. And again, it's important that result was passed by reference in order to maintain those changes.
Alright.
kylie jue: So moving on.
We go ahead and make this big again.
kylie jue: It was a challenge for home and I encourage you not to look this up, try to see if you can figure it out. How would you generalize the solution to end this instead of three and we left the sort of open
kylie jue: Question with a sample function, you could fill in at home for on your own. If you're interested in this problem.
kylie jue: We'll come back to this problem later as we're learning about more topics in the quarter, but even just thinking about
kylie jue: How would you generalize your solution to end this instead of three. So if you had on that source peg, not just three but more discs.
kylie jue: I encourage you to think about it, it's kind of fun. Alright, so let's go ahead and move on to the new topics for today, which are an ordered a teaser on ordered abstract data structures.
kylie jue: And so
kylie jue: What are some examples or why would we even use these unaltered data structures or like order data structures as we saw sort of give us this nice structure to the information that we're using. But here's some examples of data where you wouldn't actually want to just have
kylie jue: Numerical indexes. So you might think about just tracking, who are the unique visitors to a website, you have a shuffled playlist where order doesn't matter. And you don't want duplicate songs
kylie jue: Maybe you want to have particular people and their passport numbers for a flight.
kylie jue: A recipe with ingredients and the number or the quantities of each ingredient and products placed into categories and online storefront
kylie jue: So like on Amazon, when you're shopping and you shop by category. It wouldn't make any sense of all of those products were just given an index or a number, but rather you look them up by category.
kylie jue: And so I just want to clarify when I say an ordered versus ordered were specifically referring to numerical ordering. So what we were talking about with indices. So even in queues and stacks, there is a specific ordering in terms of number
kylie jue: Even though you're not able to access the elements that way. And so the data types, we're talking about today do not have indices or numerical
kylie jue: Number associations with each of the elements
kylie jue: Yeah. And sometimes it's not actually efficient to store to store items using those indices. So the first arm data structure that we're going to talk about is sets. So what is a set a set is a collection of elements with no duplicates.
kylie jue: And so this is an example of a set of strings, where there are no duplicate strings and because there are no duplicate sets are a lot faster than order data structures like vectors.
kylie jue: We will learn later in the quarter exactly what the underlying implementation details are that make it so
kylie jue: Efficient, but again, since this is an abstract data type. We're not going to worry about how its implemented underneath.
kylie jue: We'll just know that because there are no duplicates. And the way it's implemented. It's a lot faster. And we're actually going to informally define how do you quantify what do we mean by faster in Thursday's lecture so stay tuned for that.
kylie jue: And again that's don't have indices. So here are the important methods and again
kylie jue: The data structures, we're talking about today we're going to learn about specifically the Stanford c++ library versions of them and will always link the documentation in the slides.
kylie jue: But the ones that are important to really know for sets are adding. So adding value to a set
kylie jue: You can check whether a set contains a particular value. Remember, we had a lot of questions with the vector of why can't we just say like, does the vector contain this, we have to actually loop over it.
kylie jue: With the SET WHEN YOU LOOK FOR A contains it's actually a lot faster than looping over every single item as you would have to end up vector, you can remove a value from a set and then it also knows its size and whether or not it's empty.
kylie jue: So here's an example of how you would use it you could declare a set like this and then you would just add things to it. And remember, there is no
kylie jue: There are no indices associated with each of these things. You could also just do like we'd have before. Use the curly bracket notation to declare the set
kylie jue: And then this is a new term, but just something to note for print statements sort of separate from sets. If you use this term blow off know blah for inside of a see out or inside of a print statement anything in between these two.
kylie jue: Excuse me if it's a Boolean, it will print is actually the words. True or false, instead of one or zero. So that's just sort of a convenience. If you're trying to print, true, false, and you're printing out a Boolean type
kylie jue: So what this will print out is this will print out false because Voldemort is not inside of the set friends. And then what this will do is it will iterate over all of the items inside of a set and
kylie jue: Just note here that again since there are no indices, we're not doing
kylie jue: An eye counter during this for the we're doing a for each loop. So for each string inside of the set friends print out the person
kylie jue: And this is what you'll see in the console. If you were to run this code you'd have false and then Kylie Nick and trip.
kylie jue: This is this quick side note, not something we expect you to remember. But you will notice as you're working with sets and some of these other on order data structures.
kylie jue: That for strings in particular, they're stored alphabetically. And again, that has to do with the underlying implementation, which we'll talk about more later.
kylie jue: The other really cool thing about sets is if you are a
kylie jue: If you are someone who studies math or has learned about set theory in math. You can actually perform set operations on this set data structure as well. And if you don't know what that means, yet I'll explain it. So don't worry about it.
kylie jue: But first off you can compare them just like you can with other data structure, you would have you can do the equals equals or the not equals
kylie jue: Two. And these expressions will evaluate to true if the sex contain the exact same elements or if they don't contain the exact same elements. And then there are the set operations.
kylie jue: So if you want to Union. The two sets. So basically, combining all of the things. And so one and so
kylie jue: You would do as one plus as to, you can also do s one plus equals as to so you can do that sort of shorthand addition as well.
kylie jue: You can also do as one times as to and what this gives you is the intersection. So the difference here is anything that is only inset one or only in set, you will not be included in the intersection
kylie jue: It is only elements that appear in both sets. And again, you can do times equals as well here. And then lastly, you can do
kylie jue: As one minus S two and this will give you the difference. So in this case, the order of these two does matter, it will return the difference by removing all of the elements from S to that are also in S one, so all you get are the elements that are only in S one
kylie jue: Alright so common set patterns and pitfalls. Again, you want to use a for each loop here to iterate over the set and you will iterate over each element.
kylie jue: And you don't want to ever try to use an index. So never do this, this will just break your program. So don't use indices when you're working with us.
kylie jue: All right before I move on. Actually, let me go ahead and do this example code and then I will stop for questions about sets because this might answer some of your questions so
kylie jue: As a lecture example today that we're going to return to you. I'm going to go ahead and live code this program that is going to get the number or not the number, it's going to find the unique words in a file make this a little bigger.
kylie jue: Is that OK size wise for folks.
kylie jue: So what we're doing here is we have a main function that calls a program called unique word program. And this is already
kylie jue: We've already pre written. And the reason for this is you're going to see similar code in assignment to for reading in a file where we don't expect you to write all of the code yourself, we give it to you.
kylie jue: But we'd like you to just look at it and make sure you understand what's going on. So how are we building in a file.
kylie jue: I'll go back to this wild true because this is what helped us with the console program. But what we basically will say is, we're going to get the name of a file from the user.
kylie jue: And then if they insert an empty string. We're just going to break out of our console program and then we want to read in the files lines into a vector. So, these are the files that exist.
kylie jue: Inside of my starter code here and this started code is posted on the lecture on the website as well.
kylie jue: We're going to create a stream. Again, don't worry if you don't know what a stream is
kylie jue: We're going to provide this code to you on assignment to but we also are going to create a vector.
kylie jue: And then this is the code that basically says, Take my vector and read all of the lines in one of these text file. So if I go ahead and open one of these text files, it'll go through line by line in this dot txt file.
kylie jue: And each line is going to be an entry into my vector. So that will be the first thing in my vector. That will be the second. This will be the third, etc.
kylie jue: So that's what this code is doing and basically all you need to know is that by the end of this block of code which you will again see an assignment to and need to duplicate
kylie jue: You will have a vector of the lines from a dot txt file.
kylie jue: Alright, so that's sort of the pre written code. Now what we want to do is I want to actually say now that we have this vector of lines.
kylie jue: I want to get the unique words in this TXT file. So we're, what we're going to do today is we're going to fill in this function called generate unique words.
kylie jue: Which takes an asset that you're going to modify that is going to contain the unique words and then it also takes in this lines vector that we pre populated.
kylie jue: Something else. I'm going to point out here is this word concept. So this is a new term that we haven't seen before.
kylie jue: But what's important about this function generate unique words is that we're going to populate the unique words set
kylie jue: But we're just sort of using this lines vector as a way to get the words, but we're not going to modify this lines vector at all, but we want to pass it in by reference because you can imagine as these text files get really big.
kylie jue: You don't want to just create copies of all these lines, otherwise you just have like a lot of data duplicated.
kylie jue: So what we want to do instead is we're going to say, Okay, we're going to pass it by reference because it's an abstract data structure that is really big.
kylie jue: But we're going to say in this function, I am not going to modify lines. And in fact, if I do modify lines. That's a mistake, but we don't want to actually edit any of the lines up here because we might need them later.
kylie jue: So what I do is I say concert, which means that this this parameter will not be changing inside of this function. So that's just a keyword that is new. You might see it in section or in assignments.
kylie jue: But basically what it does is if you're passing large data structures by reference. It allows you to say. Actually, I'm not going to edit it in this function. I'm just passing by reference for efficiency purposes.
kylie jue: Alright, so that's a little bit of an just an overview of what we're doing. So again, as a reminder, what are we doing, we're taking a text file and we want to find all of the unique words. So I'm going to show you how to do that using our new data structure the set
kylie jue: So first what we want to do is we want to iterate over all of these lines. So what I'm going to do is I'm going to say four string line in lines.
kylie jue: And then now what we have is a single string that is one line of text. So, for example, like one line here.
kylie jue: And so what I want to do is I want to get specific words. So what I need to do is I need to break up these
kylie jue: Lines by spaces. So the stream library and Stanford actually has this really nice function called string split where you can pass in a string and then a delay limiter character. And so for those of you coming from
kylie jue: Python, you may be familiar with the term the limiter character. What that means is, where do I want to split or separate the string.
kylie jue: And what this function nicely returns this utility function is a vector of strength. So I'm going to call this words. So this gives me back a vector of words, based on where the spaces in my string are. And now what I want to do is I want to iterate over the words. So for word in words.
kylie jue: What I just want again, I just want to find the unique words. So all I have to do here is all I'm going to do is I'm going to take unique words. And I'm going to add the word
kylie jue: And the nice thing is, since it's a set, it doesn't matter if I'm adding a duplicate word if it's a duplicate it just won't add it to my set and then up here.
kylie jue: When I call this function on populating the unique word set and then this is going to tell me how many unique words are contained just by calling size on the set. So let's go ahead and see it run
Okay.
kylie jue: So here is my console program. Can I make it bigger, more account. So please enter the file name, you would like to process. I'm going to go ahead and since this isn't a rest folder. I just have to say rose first
kylie jue: Okay dream dot txt this file contains 637 unique words and then we can continue since again this is in a while true loop up here. It's a console program that will keep repeating until I just give it a carriage return. So if I wanted to do Hamlet dot txt
kylie jue: Now, and had 7808 words and then if I just had to hit Enter. It'll finish the console program.
kylie jue: Alright so that was an example of how you might use sets to do some data processing on a large text file like getting the number of unique words.
kylie jue: What questions do you folks have about sets. Actually, let me leave this up while we do that. Is there anything in the chat. First off, Nick. That would be good to mention out loud.
Nick Bowman: Uh, yeah, I just answered this, but if you want to talk about what why can you just, you said that sets don't have duplicates. But then you potentially just added a bunch of the same words to the set. So as that allowed or how does that work.
kylie jue: Yeah, so this ad function is sort of nice in that it doesn't really matter if you're adding a duplicate into the set, it just won't include
Nick Bowman: It.
kylie jue: So that's that will do that automatically
kylie jue: So the kind of nice thing is when you're doing your data processing. You don't need to do a sort of like if set already contains word
kylie jue: Then add or if if that does not already contain the word then add it, you can just add them and the set will automatically if it's something that's in there already just won't duplicate it. Yeah.
kylie jue: It's sort of a feature of the data structure. Does that answer the question.
kylie jue: Cool. Other questions about sets.
haoming li: Yeah. One question that English because I'm pulling that were splitting those lines find off base.
haoming li: Is Oh, things are sets na word set that includes the punctuations right there was moving
kylie jue: Yeah, that's a great point. So since we're just splitting on the space character. Let's see if I can find an example.
kylie jue: By open up this one right like one word would be this. So you're right, it would include the punctuation. In this case,
kylie jue: And in this case, like you'd have dreamed with a with these quotation marks after it. Right. Yeah. And something this is actually, it's a good segue.
kylie jue: I'm not going to show you how to do it in lecture today.
kylie jue: But in your second assignment, you're actually going to have to figure out how do you trim this punctuation or remove this punctuation when you're looking at words. And that's something you'll learn how to do in the first assignment. But yeah, that's a good
kylie jue: It's a good note that this is not a perfect word count because it's including some things with punctuation and some things without. Yeah, good point. Thank you.
Other questions about sense
Alright.
kylie jue: If not, I'm going to go ahead and move
kylie jue: On to take a quick break for announcements. So quick announcement breaks reminder again assignment. One is, do tonight at 11:59pm in your time zone and assignment to will be out by the end of the day tomorrow trip is going to host. Yeah. Ours your early assignment help
kylie jue: On Thursday, this Thursday at 7pm PDT will send out the zoom info soon. And again, those will be recorded, so if you aren't able to attend in person or if you're a minor and can't attend in person that recording will be posted right after
kylie jue: Um, and then just as a note the schedule page on the course website. Some folks were asking for. What are some additional resources for learning about the topics that are covered in lecture.
kylie jue: We do have the course reader the book.
kylie jue: And it's optional reading. But if you are thinking, hey, I'd like some more review on this particular topic or this particular data structure we posted the associated readings that correspond to the book with the lecture so highly recommend taking a look at those.
kylie jue: If you want some extra review of the concepts and then one last note that we've been realizing, or seeing and layer as a pattern.
kylie jue: Please don't forget to include an actual zoom link. When you sign up for layer, otherwise the section leader has a little bit of a hard time contacting you, so there's a field and layer.
kylie jue: Where you can put in a zoom link and make sure that link has an associated password because Stanford's requiring that now, or if you put in the zoom ID. Don't forget to include the password in your request as well. So just the note on when you're signing up for there.
Alright.
kylie jue: So with that, let's go ahead and move on to our second data structure or second an order data structure for day to day which is maps.
kylie jue: So what does a map a map is a collection of key value pairs. So really emphasis on the Paris here.
kylie jue: And the key is what's used to quickly find the value. So for example, here we have keys on the left.
kylie jue: With some phone numbers which are the values on the right. So Christmas phone number would be best Jenny's phone or the best. And again, this is the key. And this is the value in the pair.
kylie jue: Other terms you'll hear from a map or a dictionary and Python. So if you're coming from Python. Same thing as addict. You also may hear it called an associated
kylie jue: Associative array, and I believe in Java. It was pretty much just called them map or a hash map and a map is an alternative to an order data structure where the indices no longer need to be integers. So what do I mean by that, basically, instead of this being like 1234
kylie jue: You actually have other data types that can act as your indices are the keys inside of your data structure for these values.
kylie jue: So there's a lot of different map methods. And again, this is not even comprehensive, I'm just trying to get to fit on one slide.
kylie jue: There are a lot of different things you can do with them. And the other thing is with maps. They're often different ways you can do it. There's often a method that you can use as well as this sort of way of indexing into the map using the key.
kylie jue: So these are some of the functions that you will see
kylie jue: And again, for an exhaustive list. Check out the Stanford documentation here and I'll go over an example with a map. So you can see some of the core things that you might use. So some of the examples. Again, this is how you would create a map, you can use the curly bracket notation again.
kylie jue: If you would like, but this would just be creating an empty map and then you can add things in using this square bracket notation. So this is the key. So if you wanted to add Jenny's phone number to your phone book.
kylie jue: You would use the key and outside the square brackets and then you put the value over here.
kylie jue: Something else to notice again this map has to you have to tell it what types. You're expecting this first one is the type of the key and the second one is the type of the value
kylie jue: And then alternative way to do this is to use the put function or the put method on the map and do the key and then the value pastor
kylie jue: Let's see. So then the other thing you could do is you don't have to just use this for assignment. You can also use this to get values that are already stored inside of your map.
kylie jue: So here, if you wanted to get Jenny's number you could index into the map using journeys name or the key and then it would store the value inside of this new variable string. And again, you can use get here as well. And if you see out at this number, it would just be the value over here.
kylie jue: Just a quick note on nested data structures. We've talked sort of not officially about it but we mentioned, like you can have
kylie jue: 2D vectors and that sort of thing. But basically takeaway is you can have these nested data structures where, for example, in a map, you could have your string your keys be a string.
kylie jue: And you can have the values actually be another data structure. So this might be something like, maybe you have a bank account where you have
kylie jue: The string is the name of the person or the ID. And then inside of here, you're storing a bunch of charges like negative and positive amounts that you're withdrawing or adding to the account. So it's a vector of doubles instead of just a single number.
kylie jue: Yeah, all right. Oh, yes. And so that's inserting new values. And then this is accessing values common map patterns and pitfalls.
kylie jue: We use the for each loop to iterate over maps. Very similar to sets because there are no indices. So in this case, when you say for. And then, again, this is the type that you're using for the key in your map.
kylie jue: So in this case, it would be a string, but for the type of key in map and then you can iterate over all of the values of your map by using map and then indexing in with the key.
kylie jue: One thing that's important to note, this is very similar to the pitfall. We mentioned with queues and stacks where you don't want to get the size inside of a for loop and then change the map. So I changed the data structure inside of your loop.
kylie jue: What you don't want to do here is you don't want to be removing keys while you're inside of this loop or as you're iterating because that will cause a bug.
kylie jue: Because you're trying to iterate over the keys and if you remove one, it's your editing the data structure will also iterating over so bad times. Don't do that.
kylie jue: What you could do instead actually is useless. So you would say for type Kirk key.
kylie jue: Map key. So this is a map method that returns a vector of keys.
kylie jue: And that vector is a copy of the keys. It's not editing the actual keys in your map. It's finding all the keys in your map and then to putting it into a vector, and then you're iterating over the Spectre. So when you do something like this.
kylie jue: It is ok to edit the map inside of this loop because basically these functions that the map has the dark values and keys. Make a copy of either the values of the keys. So if you do want to use a for loop to iterate and edit your map use these functions, instead of doing it that way.
kylie jue: Alright, so that's one common Matt pattern or pitfall this other one is actually a really cool feature of maps and C plus plus, while also potentially being very dangerous.
kylie jue: So what we're going to learn about is auto insert and this is something that you probably won't have seen if you're coming from Java or Python.
kylie jue: Particularly, not with Python.
kylie jue: But what you'll have is suppose I'm trying to create a frequency map where I'm just getting words or strings from the user and counting how many times they're giving me the string.
kylie jue: So I have my wild true loop here and I'm going to get some text from the user. And then I'm going to see out the number of times I've seen that text. So in other languages right here. As soon as I said frequency map text if my map is empty.
kylie jue: This would give me an error or this would cause a bug, right, because the text this key doesn't yet exist in the map.
kylie jue: But what c++ actually does is when it knows when you use this notation, it automatically inserts the key text into the map. If it doesn't already exist.
kylie jue: So what would this do for the very first time I'm going to this while loop. If I give it sort of some random text like my name Kylie
kylie jue: What it would do is it would try to index into the map and say, oh, Kylie is not a key in my map.
kylie jue: So I'm going to add it and it adds a default value in this case because it's storing incentive. It'll just say frequency map Kylie equals zero. So what we'll see out here. It'll see out zero
kylie jue: And then on this next line. It'll increments account to one automatically. So what's really cool is that this while loop will work without any
kylie jue: Extra like if statements to check if the key is already in the map or anything like that auto insert allows this block of code to just work for you. And that is a special feature of c++ and maps and c++
kylie jue: Copy up though. Suppose I'm instead writing a block of code where rather than just like
kylie jue: Showing the frequencies and getting information from the user. Maybe I get the key somewhere in. But here, and then I want to say, okay, well, I want to check to see if this key is in my map. So what I'm gonna do is I'm going to say
kylie jue: If the frequency map key is equal to zero. See out. Okay, then I know the keys in my mind.
kylie jue: So they have this block of code is just testing. Oh, I want to say I want to find out is this key in my map.
kylie jue: This actually will not work because this will always be true if the key was not in your map that auto insert will automatically insert it into the map at this step, and it's a little bit
kylie jue: off putting. Because you don't expect it to just happen in the middle of an if statement.
kylie jue: But it will, as soon as you use this notation map and then square brackets key. If the key is not in there, it'll automatically insert. So this will cause a bug, because this will always be true. And so no matter what key are trying to check it will always say that the key is in the map.
kylie jue: The way to resolve that is to use this function contains key instead. So then what you're not using a square bracket mutation. And you can say, does the map contain the key, key and then this will correctly evaluate true or false depending on if the key was already in the map or not.
kylie jue: Alright, so just something to keep in mind when you're using maps and using auto answer. It's very powerful, but also can be confusing you for trying to check if something is in the map already or not.
kylie jue: So again, I'm going to
kylie jue: Open
Nick Bowman: With something from it, which is very tricky, but good to know. Kelly mentioned that there oftentimes multiple ways to do things with maps. So, for example, for getting values. There's the square brackets syntax or the
Nick Bowman: method, the method will not do auto insertion very tricky feature I guess but auto insertion only happens when you're accessing with the square bracket operators.
kylie jue: Although this documentation Nick says that if
Nick Bowman: The default value.
Nick Bowman: Oh okay nevermind I will try that out. Then I there was one. Okay, nevermind. There was, there was something that didn't do the auto insertion, I might just be something else. Sorry. Okay.
Nick Bowman: No worries. Yeah.
kylie jue: Yeah. And if you're ever unsure about whether or not this method.
kylie jue: Specifically because these methods are more Stanford c++ specific definitely just check out the documentation. If you have a question about like doesn't do what you expect, with the square brackets. Yeah.
kylie jue: Alright, moving forward. I'm going to go ahead and do I'm going to extend our unique words program. So suppose now I don't just want the unique words in the program. But I also want to know how many times each word appears
kylie jue: With the caveat that helming mentioned of sometimes this may not be 100% accurate because we're going to get some punctuation as well.
kylie jue: But let's go ahead and do this. So now what I want to say is I'm going to add in this block of code that's already there. So in addition to just printing out how many unique words I have
kylie jue: I also want to print out how many times some of these unique words appear and just for the sake of
kylie jue: Printing I'm going to limit it to 10. So what this is doing. You don't have to worry too much about it. But basically, once I populate this word counts map. I'm only going to look at the first 10 just so that I'm not printing a giant list of words.
kylie jue: But what we're going to worry about is this function generate word counts. And so what we do is we're creating a map that we're going to pass by reference and edit and again we pass in our lines as a concept vector
kylie jue: And I want to populate this map of word counts to show how many times does each unique word appear
kylie jue: So you'll notice this. I'm going to start reading it, but it's going to look very similar to this genuine generate unique words.
kylie jue: Function as well. So again, what we want to do, right, is we want to iterate over all the lines first and then once we've iterated over the lines. I'm actually just going to do this, um,
kylie jue: We are going to create a vector of the words again because we want to split it. And then we want to iterate over all the words. So now we want to figure out, okay,
kylie jue: This part looks the same, but now we want to figure out how to add it to our word counts.
kylie jue: And here we're going to go ahead and take advantage of our auto insert and do this word counts word. So even if the word is not already in the map. This will automatically add it with a default value of zero.
kylie jue: And then I'm going to say plus equal one. And actually, just as a note here. This is the same thing as if I had done this.
kylie jue: word counts word is equal to word counts word plus one, those, those two lines are exactly the same. I can substitute them for each other and the auto insert will
kylie jue: Will work for either case. Let me fix that spelling. There you go.
kylie jue: Alright, so let's go ahead and see what the stats. So again, it's only a one line difference here this
kylie jue: Over here, we're adding it to a set. In this case, we're just adding it to a map of counts, where the key is the word and the value is the number of times that the word appears in our text. So let me go ahead and run this.
Let's
Make this bigger and let's do this.
kylie jue: Alright, so
kylie jue: So this file contains 637 unique words.
kylie jue: And you'll notice that, again, these are actually similar to set these are actually printing in alphabetical order by ASCII value of the first character in the string so capital letters are going to be first and then you get these punctuation marks.
kylie jue: Oh, sorry. No, these are actually quotation marks on the first time using the string.
kylie jue: So again, not perfect, but that is what you'll get. With that, let me see if I can do one that shows a little bit of a better
kylie jue: Word. Yeah. So this actually reveals a
kylie jue: You could consider it a bug, but something that we really don't want we already know we're not properly pulling out punctuation based on these letters. Right. And again, this is
kylie jue: Because we're doing a sub list of the first 10 things in our keys. It's always going to give us the ones of punctuation first because they're going to appear alphabetically first
kylie jue: I encourage you, if you want to see more of these words just change this number from 10 to something larger so that you can see more of the actual words.
kylie jue: But one thing that's kind of weird here is I have this key that's empty and it's appearing 19,000 times in my program.
kylie jue: So what's happening is when I use this string split it's splitting on the spaces, but it's adding the empty string.
kylie jue: That's one of the things that it's putting into my math. So just to avoid this. Let's go ahead and do this. So if word is equal to the empty string. We don't want to add it. So I'm going to go ahead and put a not here and this should help with getting rid of that.
Random 19,000 appearance empty string.
And let's do Hamlet again.
kylie jue: Yeah, and so it got rid of that large count one, and I believe this number probably changed as well, although I didn't double check that. Cool. And then you can experiment with this on your own. The file is there again. You just have to make sure to put rose in the front.
kylie jue: And you can see different different texts. These are actually the full text of all these things and what the word counts look like for those. So with that, I'm going to go ahead and pause and check if there are questions about this code or about maps in general.
Also going to take out the extra handle here cuz that's too much space.
No question. Oh, I see. Edward raises.
edouard des: A question about the you were talking about that empty space that appears that because of the. So if you use the string split method. It'll add empty strings to the, um, to your to the bathroom.
kylie jue: I think what's happening is if I go to some of these. I don't know that I'm going to see a good example. I have to find one. But some of these basically may have like double spaces.
kylie jue: And so if there's like a double space between yeah like this. This is a double space between a sentence right so if you split on the space character you have
kylie jue: This word right that's the first word, and then you have a space and then it brings takes the empty string as a word because there's another space and then another space and then you so well. This
kylie jue: This empty character gets added as a key into the map or it gets pulled out one the split because there's two spaces around it. Does that make sense.
edouard des: Yeah, I think so. We're just looking for
kylie jue: Someone else I saw, I saw a hand go up, but I don't. I didn't catch the name
Demi Lei: Okay, so, um, I'm just wondering for the auto insert like under what kind of circumstance would that happen like is that when you're trying to access the key that it doesn't really exist, and they would like auto inserted for or
kylie jue: Yeah, exactly. So anytime you do this. So whether this this expression is in an if statement if it's something like this where you're assigning it
kylie jue: Anytime.
kylie jue: You do that it will check to see if this key already exists in the map and then auto insert it with a default value if it does not already exist. Yeah.
Demi Lei: Got it. Thank you.
Nick Bowman: All right. Okay. I just put together a quick
Nick Bowman: Quote example and I think I figured out what the difference in behaviors and it's it's even more subtle than I thought initially
kylie jue: Versus the
Nick Bowman: Yeah, so that
Nick Bowman: Yeah, yeah. Sorry. Yeah. So it's the difference between
Nick Bowman: Gentleman the square operators and the dot yet function will return value to you if the key is not in the map, but it will not insert. So, for example, like the key will not permanently exist in the map.
Nick Bowman: But if you access with the square bracket after it square bracket operators afterwards. The, the key will permanently exist in afterwards, if that makes sense.
kylie jue: I see. So what this if I did, so if I did something like this. And the word did not exist in the map.
kylie jue: Like if I just didn't see out this
kylie jue: Yeah, it would see out
kylie jue: Zero, because that word hasn't
kylie jue: Existed before, but the word itself would not get stored as a key and the map it sort of just doesn't fail. It gives you a default value.
Nick Bowman: But it doesn't
Nick Bowman: Store. The key.
Nick Bowman: Is that you're saying yes. Okay. Great.
Good to know.
kylie jue: Um. Was there another hand.
Nick Bowman: Or today.
kylie jue: If not, I'm actually I'll stick around for questions after if there are more questions about maps, but I just noticed it's 1220
kylie jue: So,
kylie jue: In summary, we are done. We're pretty much done here you these are the things you've learned, we've learned about ordered ones. And we've learned about on ordered ones.
kylie jue: And in particular, the unaltered agencies are useful when numerical ordering of the data is not optimal.
kylie jue: big takeaway here is that it's important to match the structure or the data structure with the purpose that you want to solve with the purpose of what you're using it for
kylie jue: In order to have a more efficient solution or more, or more efficient code. So really think about what you're doing and which structure would be most suited for that. What's next tomorrow. Nick is going to go through a work example that goes through some of these data types.
kylie jue: At TS, that will be really useful for launching you into assignment to
kylie jue: Specifically, it's going to have to do with
kylie jue: This which, if any of you have ever done a word ladder from going
Nick Bowman: From one word to the other.
kylie jue: That will be what he's going
Nick Bowman: Over tomorrow.
kylie jue: And then on Thursday. We're going to talk
kylie jue: A lot more about concretely explaining what do we mean when we keep saying algorithmic efficiency or something is faster than something
kylie jue: Else.
kylie jue: And we're going to define that really
kylie jue: All right, we'll stick around for questions. Thank you.
Nick Bowman: Yeah, and
Nick Bowman: Getting the questions for you that are watching you can feel free to stop now actual content will stop request record the q&a afterwards.
Weiqi Yu: So keep the recording.
Thank you.
Elena Williams: Thank you. Thank you.
tongjun zhang: Thank you.
kylie jue: I think I saw
ian rundle: If you
kylie jue: Go up first.
And then
Kenneth Fischer: Kind of wants to go. So I was wondering if the maps order things up a bit uglier by numerical order.
kylie jue: Yeah, so the. It depends on the
kylie jue: Data Type that's getting stored is the key. And this is dependent on actually how the map is being implemented underneath the hood for this type of map in particular for strings. It's going to be alphabetical by ASCII value.
kylie jue: But again, it's going to depend on the
kylie jue: Type of math. And so you won't be able to like index in again. But that will be the order of the keys under that
Kenneth Fischer: Okay. And do you set. Are they ordered in the same way that that. Yes. Okay. Thank you.
kylie jue: And then I saw
Nate Hedgecock: Two quick questions. One, so the word counts word plus equals one down there. So the main difference between like what we might have seen in and want to succeed with Python.
Nate Hedgecock: Is that, like, initially I don't remember exactly how it works. But initially, like you had to initialize the word to zero.
kylie jue: Exactly.
Nate Hedgecock: And then go back in and then set the word equal to the word right
Yeah.
kylie jue: I'm sorry, go ahead. I didn't mean to cut you off. Would you say
Nate Hedgecock: So in this case, that the added efficiency. There is just like it'll automatically insert into it without having to go through exactly what you're doing now.
kylie jue: Exactly. Um, so in Python or something like this before.
Nate Hedgecock: Then, and then
Nate Hedgecock: With that, so it auto inserts and you said it sets it to a default variable. But like, how does it know so like, you know, my key might be
Nate Hedgecock: You know the word. It might not be a word count it might be something else. It might be like your example, phone numbers or something like that. What is the default variable.
Nate Hedgecock: And then like, how does it know what to default the variable to, I guess, is the question.
kylie jue: Yeah. So that depends on the type that's getting stored as the value. So if it's an integer that you're storing as a value. It's going to default to zero. If it's a string, it's going to default to the empty string.
kylie jue: Yeah, it just depends on the type that's getting stored as the value. I'm not actually I don't remember my memory, all the different ones that end up as default, but you can sort of experiment with those depending on what how you declare your map here and what you say the value type is
Nate Hedgecock: So, so it might be the case that you want it. You want it to auto insert and then you'll say something like, if it's
Nate Hedgecock: You know, if it's auto inserted set set of equal to this to start out with, or something like that. Like you'd have to have another line of code that says like, now that you've auto inserted the key. This is the value I want associated with it.
kylie jue: Yeah, that's a good point. So, like, for example, if you wanted to, for some reason, you wanted to initialize all the initial word counts to to
kylie jue: The auto insert wouldn't really be doing what you want it to. Right. You'd, it would be inserting zero there. But you would have to manually say, oh, this is the first time I'm seeing the word set the value to to. Yeah.
Nate Hedgecock: Got it. All right, thanks.
Nick Bowman: Any problem. Oh.
Sure, yeah.
Pablo Manjon Gamez: I had like two questions. First question is for a map, can you choose what the default value would be
kylie jue: So, so for the inserting for the auto inserting it so I don't think you can't set it and Nick, correct me if I'm wrong, it is dependent on the type. So if you if it's not, if the type doesn't have the default that you want it to. You're going to still have to initialize it yourself.
Pablo Manjon Gamez: Okay, for
Pablo Manjon Gamez: Most operations and sets where you do plus equals four times and that stuff is that was that made as sort of like a donor method. If you know those from Python. Where does
Pablo Manjon Gamez: Yeah, you know, done their methods for Python is that the same sort of thing for sense
kylie jue: I'm not super familiar with how dunder methods are related in c++ or if they're even possible.
kylie jue: So I would have to look into that. I don't know off the top of my head. Yeah.
All right.
kylie jue: Me. Do you have a question or is that just a real tangible
Demi Lei: But yes, I have a question. So, um, well, one is that I'm when I'm Nick was talking about the DOD get think I still don't really get, like, you know, because in the documentation. It says that, you know, if the key is not under it would automatically like DOD add that key.
Demi Lei: But I don't get, like, you know, like how it was saying that like when you're trying to see out that it's not giving you the thing so
Nick Bowman: Just, just go to the experience and test out CPP
Nick Bowman: And you can
Nick Bowman: I'm sorry, the test workspace and
Nick Bowman: It seems like you're there.
Nick Bowman: To clarify,
Nick Bowman: Did a bit of remembering that stuff was from the slides and Chris was all wrong about that. So we'll just have to go back and change it. The get function will not add a key.
Nick Bowman: So yeah, so if you run the run this code as, as you see it when you run this code FRIENDS DIED returns and empty streets, but gives you a deeper value.
kylie jue: Next audio is cutting out here. Let me go ahead
kylie jue: And just show up on this day and
Nick Bowman: Then what we want to do is see out
Is it in the map.
Actually, let's just do that.
Um,
kylie jue: Yeah, so that's just a lot of come to school. So we have an empty map and then we're going to see using the dot get method is Nick in the map. So I'm going to say make around
kylie jue: So get you'll notice
kylie jue: This will this won't actually return anything. So that's fine. That makes sense. And then we asked is it in the is Nick and the map. So we're saying, does the friends map contain the key Nick and it's actually false here. But what we're showing here is it doesn't
kylie jue: It doesn't crash. It's not giving zero though either now is that
Expected
Nick Bowman: The phone
Nick Bowman: Is frozen.
kylie jue: Maybe. Oh, sorry. Is maybe it's clear. If I do this, let's do this.
I'm going to separate this into a different line.
Just to make it super clear
kylie jue: Okay, yeah. So it does look like it. It won't crash here, but it is not adding it into the map. Does that make sense to me.
Demi Lei: Yeah, yeah. Just cuz into my dad says that if it's not there. Oh madly
kylie jue: Yeah, actually say that in the documentation to
Demi Lei: Sure. I like I think on this slide.
Nick Bowman: Yeah it so
Nick Bowman: This is correct, like what it says in the documentation, there is correct, it will give you the value, but it will not ask if that makes sense.
kylie jue: Yes, turns the value associated with the key in the map, but if the key is not found rather than adding it, it actually just returns the default value for that specific type that's the correct documentation. This was copied from the previous quarters.
So I think that was wrong.
Demi Lei: Okay, got it. And I'm just one more thing like this auto insert thing is that in the standard map or is that just a Stanford map thing.
kylie jue: I believe that's in the standard map to do, you know, Nick, if that's true.
Nick Bowman: There is a way to there's method you can call on the standard maps that will do auto insertion, but actually gets the default behavior. So it's the default behavior in the Stanford libraries.
Nick Bowman: But it's not. I don't think it's the default behavior. There is a way to
Nick Bowman: On that, too, but
Nick Bowman: Um, but yeah. It's been a while since I use the c++ map so
kylie jue: I think I'd have to we'd have to look into the documentation to see. So I think what it sounds like, if I'm remembering correctly, is I'm summarizing it because your audio keeps cutting out
kylie jue: Is that the map on the standard map, there's a way to set it so that you can have it to auto insertion, but the default is not to auto insert unlike with the Stanford c++ where default on, sir.
Demi Lei: Oh ok so like is that in the standard CPP madly, you can kind of, I think I remember somebody before as I like. You can set the auto insert to something like that kind of something good day.
Stuff.
kylie jue: I guess that there's this function which is inserted or assigned. So if it doesn't already exist, you can automatically assign it to a default value. So that's the alternate like it actually has separate functions for inserting versus insert or assign
Demi Lei: Yeah, I got it. Thank you.
kylie jue: Alright, I'm actually, I realized I have office hours right now. So I'm going to hop over to the other call but I'll let Nick continue answering questions in here. I'm going to stop sharing my screen.
I can figure out how
The little zoom thing disappear.
Nick Bowman: Yeah, Scott. I just saw your question about the values can be data structures. So you can you can absolutely nice data structures as the values and maps and you're, you're not on the second side.
Nick Bowman: And we may see an example of that tomorrow if we have time, but
Nick Bowman: Did you have a question.
kathleen bryan: Yeah. Can you hear me.
kathleen bryan: I'm so I'm so just a little bit confused about sets. So like looking at like the name example where you have like three names in it. I wouldn't understand what would happen if you multiply a set of names with another set of names or like
kathleen bryan: Yeah, I just don't understand what the use cases for
That
Nick Bowman: So the multiplication operation rate does set intersection. So, you know, there's a lot of different cases in which set intersection is useful, right. So,
Nick Bowman: And in, you know, the one that's on the top of my head because this is what you'll do in the second assignment is if you're looking up.
Nick Bowman: For example, if you're doing search queries on the internet, right, and you say, I want to find all pages that have the word cat.
Nick Bowman: And so that can give you like a set of pages and you look up, I want to all the web pages that have the word dog, and that gives you a set of web pages.
Nick Bowman: And but perhaps you're interested in finding. I actually want to find exactly all pages that contain both the words cat and dog.
Nick Bowman: And so if you intersect, right, if you multiply those two sets of pages and you find the intersection of those pages you like there is there's a sort of meaningful result that you get out of it, which is a set that contains all the pages that have both the word cat and the Word doc.
Nick Bowman: And and so it's like set intersection is a very valuable operation and anywhere where you can represent information using sets or anywhere where it's useful to represent information using sense
Nick Bowman: And you can probably find some like meaningful way to interpret what it means to take the intersection of those two sets. Right. And if you think about the friends example right like if you have a set
Nick Bowman: With with four names in it. And those are your friends and I have a set with with three names in it. And those are my friends right
Nick Bowman: Like if you take the intersection of mindset and you're set. You've just found our mutual friends but you found the people that are both of our friends, right.
Nick Bowman: So the, the intersection and and if you wanted. Yeah. And so you can you can make some of the arguments for for the
Nick Bowman: Other set operations as well.
Nick Bowman: You kind of just have to, it will change from example. For example, what their meeting is but they all sort of will have some some important
kathleen bryan: Okay, that makes sense. So just just said, I fully understand like if I had two sets within identical list of people except for like one name john and I wanted to
kathleen bryan: Add them together then john would just be added, it would be the original names plus just john
kathleen bryan: And then if I say john out then he would come out and it would be back to the original set
Nick Bowman: Yeah. Yeah, I think so. So be careful subtraction happens between two sets. So if you took the resulting set that had everyone and john and you subtract it out a set, but just contain john
Nick Bowman: Yeah. Just going back to the original. Yeah.
Nick Bowman: Okay, you can't subtract individual elements out of a set, you can remove individual elements from a set, but I want to be clear that the subtraction operation is a set operation. So it has to operate on two sets.
kathleen bryan: So,
Nick Bowman: If you have a set continuing one person and you subtract that set from your list of friends and that person is no longer
kathleen bryan: Okay, got it. Thank you so much.
Nick Bowman: Michael, do you have a question.
Michael M Hu: Uh, yeah, I'm a little confused about the c++ maps because coming from Java.
Michael M Hu: Maps is like the, I think it's like an interface or something. And there's like all sorts of little data source that branch off of it.
Michael M Hu: Like hash maps and such. So how does like where does the c++ flap fallen to like that hierarchy.
Nick Bowman: Yeah, so
Nick Bowman: The so there are so right now we're just dealing with the data types called map and set
Nick Bowman: And we won't talk about it until the very end of the quarter. And there's no reason for you to sort of need to use it or know about it. But there is a hash map and a half second c++ as well, or in the San Fran c++ libraries as well.
Nick Bowman: And we're going to basically have actually one lecture dedicated at the end of the class to talk about
Nick Bowman: Why, like why those to exist and sort of what their what the benefits are and and along the way we'll learn sort of how both of those data structures are kind of built underneath the hood.
Nick Bowman: But that is sort of, you can think of that as like the second half of the class of the first half of the classes like using abstractions and sort of
Nick Bowman: Using the properties that they can teach us the second half of the class will be actually figuring out, okay, how do these even work.
Nick Bowman: And so we won't talk a ton about how they how they work right now, but there is a similar hash that hash map that that exists and that will talk about it.
Michael M Hu: Okay.
Nick Bowman: But for for everything that you need to do for now mapping set will be sufficient.
Michael M Hu: Great, thank you.
Jennifer Anna Bonello: I have a question. But I don't know how to raise my hand. So for maps. Is there, is there a way how to define a map with the values and keys already inside without having to add them each separate one
Nick Bowman: Um, Yes, I think so. Let me try it on really quick and then I'll paste it into the chat. So the way that it works is you have to
Nick Bowman: Use similar
Nick Bowman: Initialization syntax that you've seen with the sort of curly braces sort of how you saw with initializing a vector that already has values in it. I'm just
Double check
Nick Bowman: Okay, so this is this is what it'll look like. So say for example,
Nick Bowman: We wanted to
Nick Bowman: Yeah. So it's going to look a little weird, bro, paste it in the chat right now. So if I wanted to create a map that had two key value pairs in it.
Nick Bowman: So the, the external curly braces define the map and then there's going to be a number of sort of comma separated entries inside the map.
Nick Bowman: And every one of those entries is another set of curly braces with key comma value. So it's a little it looks a lot less nice than like the vector or the set or the things we've seen already, but it is possible
Nick Bowman: And you yeah you can basically use use that syntax, where you you make a comma separated list of sort of pairs. And each of those pairs is
Nick Bowman: Exactly to value is one key or exactly two things in one key value.
Make sense
Demi Lei: One quick question. So like, is it possible to combine two said, and two maps, just like combining two vectors or
Nick Bowman: What, what do you mean by combine
Demi Lei: Still like you know how for a vector. We can do like you know vector one plus vector to add vector to but just be like all the values in there would be basically a pen.
Demi Lei: Arm, you know,
Demi Lei: To vector wine. But is it possible to do that for set to maps or
Nick Bowman: Yeah, so for sets, right. We saw all those different setup. There's actually an even richer set of operations you can do on factors. Right. We saw plus times minus right the Union, the intersection, that the difference right
Demi Lei: Row. So like those basically kind of return stats right
Demi Lei: Okay. Okay, so
Nick Bowman: Yeah.
Demi Lei: There's, there's
Nick Bowman: Yeah, there's there's method equivalence that modify the underlying set. So I think dot dot union, intersection and
Nick Bowman: Difference will like if you really care a lot about modifying the underlying the initial set you started off with there's like parallels of them, the operators will just return the value
Nick Bowman: But the other ones will actually modify the underlying one maps is a little different. I don't think the same operators are defined on maps, but I'm actually not. Not sure if it's a little less clear what it means to like union and map because it's like, oh, these values do you
Nick Bowman: It's a more mass. I wouldn't, I would say that for maps those operations don't really make sense if you want to combine the, the, if you want to combine the contents of two maps. You'll have to make those decisions for yourself and sort of decide what you want.
Demi Lei: Okay, got it. Thank you.
haoming li: And I have question that we were talking about originally in the slides or how to use that cheese together.
haoming li: She's
haoming li: Like yeah and Carly were discussing about what about gap. So what are the defense of a gap and please. So like literally shoes.
Nick Bowman: There is not a get keys methods and untrue entirely sure there's a dot keys method.
Nick Bowman: That will give you a vector of all of the keys and map.
Nick Bowman: The dot get method takes in a single key as a parameter and will return to you if there exists one associated value with that key.
Nick Bowman: Does, does that answer the question. There is no get keys method. I'm not entirely sure what you're referencing
Why
haoming li: Yeah, I might
haoming li: Remember that you want.
Last question.
Nick Bowman: Go ahead and stop the recording and we'll see you all tomorrow.